Guide to the Stanford University, International Relations Program, Honors Theses SC4-6526 SC4-6526
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, International Relations Program, honors theses
1975-2017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. International Relations Program
SC4-6526
41.25 Linear Feet (451 volumes in 63 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University International Relations Program.
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduate students in the Stanford University International Relations Program.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the International Relations Program in several accessions between 2004 and 2010. Additional theses were received from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
International relations.; International relations.; Student papers.; Student papers.; Stanford University. International Relations Program; Stanford University. International Relations Program; Stanford University. International Relations Program; Stanford University. International Relations Program; Stanford University. International Relations Program
- Theses, 1978-1998; Accession ARCH_2005_278
  - Ablow, Ellen, Limited Integration and the European Community., 1983 (Box 7)
  - Agosti, Tam, The Status of Jerusalem- Keystone in a Final Peace Settlement., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Almirantearena, Evangelina, Spain and NATO., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Arakawa, Maki, Unusually Japanese?: The 'Comfort Women' System of World War II., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Ashraf, Nava, The European Union and Mercosur: Modeling Integration., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Baltzan, Elizabeth, Ethics in Foreign Policy: A Normative Analysis of US Policy Toward South Africa during the Reagan Administration., 1991 (Box 18)
  - Barker, Adam Howell, "Instability and Growth of the Italian National Debt, A Post-War Political History"., 1996 (Box 29)
  - Barma, Naazneen, The Indo-Nepalese Relationship: A Story of Contradictory Interests., 1996 (Box 29)
  - Barton, Mary, A Critical Analysis of Constructive Engagement in Southern Africa., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Barzelay, Michael, The Political Economy of Alcohol Energy in Brazil., 1980 (Box 4)
  - Basson, Danna, "National Ideals, Economic Realities and Political Compromises in Martinique"., 1996 (Box 29)
  - Benchekroun, Raja, The Position of Muslim Moroccan Women: Religion, Colonialism, Nationalism, and the Implications for Post-Colonial Morocco., 1993 (Box 22)
  - Bender, Ann Marie, The Student Movement and the Transition to Democracy in Chile., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Bender, Danya, The Gush Emunim: An Analysis of Alliance Building Between Religious and Secular Jews in Israel., 1987 (Box 12)
  - Berenson, Sondra J., Democracy Versus Terrorism: A Question of Balance., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Biehl, Amy, Chester Crocker and the Negotiations for Namibian Independence: The Role of the Individual in Recent American Foreign Policy., 1989 (Box 14)
  - Birmingham, Katherine, The Role of the CSCE in the New Architecture for European Security., 1991 (Box 18)
  - Blum, Jon Evan, No Hay Más Ruta Que la Nuestra: Mexican Perceptions of the 1980s., 1983 (Box 8)
  - Boggs, Hale, The Popular Movement for the Liberation of Angola: Origins, Ideology, and Achievements., 1983 (Box 8)
  - Bolash, Christopher, The British Press on the German Question., 1993 (Box 22)
  - Bonheyo, Patricia L., Václav Havel: The Politician in the Playwright., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Boyer, Jack B., Policy Alternatives in Brazilian Forestry Development., 1981 (Box 7)
  - Boyer, Jan E., Government Policy and the Textile Industry in Tanzania., 1984 (Box 9)
  - Brickeen, Marshall, The Changing Democratic Deficit in the European Union., 1995 (Box 27)
  - Bristow, Michael D., National Minorities in Western Europe: Their Struggle for Political Say and Self-Determination., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Brodlie, Matthew, The Slow Sound of His Feet: A Study of Aid and Economic Cooperation in Southern Africa., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Brooks, Sean, Tribal Sovereignty in Alaska., 1988 (Box 15)
  - Brookstone, Susan Gail, Energy Conservation in the Industrial Sector of the European Community., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Brown, Amy, "The Social Policy of the European Community: Past, Present, and Future"., 1991 (Box 20)
  - Brown, Kellee Ann, The Dynamics of Liberalization: Algeria, A Case Study., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Bryla, Erin, U.S. Army Training of Latin American Military Personnel- A Case Study: The School of the Americas., 1999 (Box 37)
  - Burns, DeAngela Jenise, All Around the World The Same Fight: African-American Influence on American Foreign Policy., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Burr, Steven J., Ostpolitik and Public Opinion in the Federal Republic of Germany 1969-1972., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Butterfield, Richard J., Spain and the European Economic Community., 1983 (Box 9)
  - Calhoun, Keith W., The Role of Culture in a Developing Nation: The National Dance Theater Company of Jamaica in a Case Study Analysis., 1977 (Box 1)
  - Calvert, Matthew, The Construction of Consensus in the Ivory Coast, and the Response of Intellectuals, 1960-1970., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Calvert, Matthew H., Democracy with Hong Kong Characteristics., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Carnes, Matthew E., The Internationalization of the Mexican Automobile Industry., 1992 (Box 22)
  - Caro, David Ricardo, The Effects on Savings and Investment of the Chilean Pension Reform of 1981: The Capitalized Pension System in Theory and in Practice., 1993 (Box 22)
  - Carpenter, Mike, The Polish Parliament, 1919-1922: An Attempt to Build a Democratic State., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Casselman, Carrie, German Unification and The Korean Experience., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Cedor, David Jay, At the Crossroads of the World: A Comprehensive History and Analysis of the Jerusalem Conflict., 1980 (Box 4)
  - Cetlin, Lisa, Postwar Visions and the Food Blockade of Germany Between the Armistice and Final Peace Settlement of World War I., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Chan, Adrian, Unilateral Confidence- Building and the Modern Nation State: Reclaiming Sovereignty in the Interest of Peace., 1988 (Box 13)
  - Chang, Anthony Tong Yi, Re-Defining the Three-Legged Stool: Finding a New Balance for Hong Kong., 1994 (Box 24)
  - Chang, David Yat-On, Prebendalism and Democratization by Decree: Creating a Third Nigerian Republic., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Chartock, Andrea, A Comparison of the Consolidation of Capitalist Democracy in Poland and Russia., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Cheek, Marney Leigh, U.S. Assistance to Poland and Hungary: How the Bush Administration and Congress shaped the support for East European Democracy Act of 1989., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Chelberg, Stephen E., Post-war Economic Policy in Japan and the United States., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Chien, Stephen, Bureaucracies as Businesses: The Strategies of Multinational Firms and Chinese Bureaucracies in China's Telecom Industry., 1998 (Box 34)
  - Chisiu, Dean, The Influence of the Public on Defense Policy in the United Kingdom and France: The INF Controversy., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Chiu, Yvonne, Agrarian Reform in Poland and Romania., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Cohn, Bill, The Refinement of Influx Control in South Africa and its Implications., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Cole, George S., Soviet Grain Reserves and Grain Storage Capacity., 1978 (Box 1)
  - Collet, Elizabeth Louise, The Economic Decline of the United States: Causes and Implications., 1991 (Box 18)
  - Corredor, Jean-Marc, The Will for Power: French and British Policies of Military Intervention in Africa after Decolonization., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Corwin, James, The International Relations of Wheat., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Dahmus, Jennifer C., The Japanese Main Firm-Supplier Relationship in the Auto Parts Industry and its Implications for U.S. Industrial Competitiveness., 1993 (Box 23)
  - de Beaurecueil, Marie Save, Franco-German Relations and the Common Agricultural Policy: National Interests and Cooperation in the European Community., 1994 (Box 24)
  - Dean, Bonnie, The United States and Japan: Alliance in Transition., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Deshpande, Rani, Alternative Trade: Theory and Practice., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Dewey, Andrea, Japan/U.S. Cross-Cultural Misunderstandings Before World War II., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Dickstein, Jonathan, Chilean Human Rights Organizations: A Study in Chilean Political Culture., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Donaldson, Victoria, Canada/United States Free Trade: Three Approaches to the Mystery., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Duggan, Charles H., ANDAVO A FARE L'AMERICA The Story of the Emigration from Barga, 1850-1924., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Dupar, Mairi, Japanese Aid to Indonesia in the Suharto Era., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Earthman, Thomas T., The management of Foreign Policy: Success and Failure in Kennedy's Collegial Approach., 1975 (Box 1)
  - Eaton, Kent, The Grace Contract as Statecraft; A Domestic Interpretation...Economic and Political Conflict Over the Construction of Railroads in Peru 1886-1890., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Edwards, Mark, Financial Liberalization in the European Community and its Effects on Economic and Monetary Union., 1992 (Box 21)
  - El Rady, Joe, Baghdad or Bust: An Analysis of the Decision to End the Persian Gulf War., 1999 (Box 37)
  - Ellemberg, Heidi, Towards a European Foreign Policy: Franco-German Relations in the Nineteen-Nineties., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Engel, Tamar, History of Japanese Attitudes towards Jews., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Ero, Victoria Penfield, United German Foreign Policy: The Case of Aid to the CSFR., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Fain, Natasha Elisa, The Chilean Women's Movement's Democratic Vision: International Relationships as Instruments of Societal Change., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Farmer, Steven, The Impact of AIDS on the Health sector in Zimbabwe: Efficacy and Sustainability of Current Policy., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Ferroni, Silvia Francesca, US and Mexican Agriculture and the North American Free Trade Agreement., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Fieglein, Ashley W., Treating an Easterner Like an Easterner: Proposal for a New Managerial Structure for Firms in the Former-GDR Using Japanese Firms as a Model., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Finney, Kristen, Le Voile Islamique Dans les Ecoles Françaises: la politique laïque remise en cause., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Fisher, Siobhán Kathleen, After the Velvet Revolution: The Czech Republic and the European Community., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Fleischner, Christopher, The Impact of Liberal Ideas: American Foreign Policy Towards German Unification in 1989-90., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Fonseca, Carlos E., The Privatization of the Mexican Banks., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Foreman, Zachary J., The Baltic States and EU Enlargement: Preserving a National Identity During Occupation, Independence and Integration., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Foster, Angel, Mobilizing Palestinian Women: The Case of Comprehensive Women's Health Care in the West Bank., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Foster, Craig, International Management: Useful Lessons from Japan., 1981 (Box 6)
  - Francis, Christopher, The Rewards of Perseverance: The Relationship between the Protestant Church and the Government of the G. D. R. 1968-1978., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Furtner, Frances Arlene, The Formulation and Implementation of Japanese Foreign Aid Policy., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Gaisford, Karin, A Critique of William Goode's Convergence Theory of Modernizing Families: Women and the changing Family in the People's Republic of China, Taiwan, and Hong Kong., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Galvan, Dennis, The American Aid Relationship with the Republic of Mali, 1960-1986., 1987 (Box 12)
  - Gamon, Catherine, The Evolution of Muslim Nationalist Ideology in Pakistan., 1979 (Box 2)
  - Gillary, Carin Lisa, The Affect of Political Stability on the Outcome of Telecommunications Privatization in Developing Countries: Case Studies of Telecommunications Privatization in Chile, Argentina and the Philippines., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Goldman, Geoffrey B., National Courts, Governments, and the European Court of Justice: A Bargaining Model of EC Legal Integration., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Gove, Amber K., Neoclassical Economics and Higher Education Policy Reform in Chile and Britain., 1997 (Box 32)
  - Gracheva, Maria, Soviet Military Unpreparedness at the Initial Stages of WWII: Causes and Consequences., 1987 (Box 12)
  - Granico, Jennifer L., Do the Association Agreements between the European Community and the nations of Poland, Hungary, and the successor states to Czechoslovakia assist in the trade re-orientation and successful economic transition of these economies?., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Green, Daniel M., Financing of Public Sector Higher Education in the Context of Wave III Private Growth: Quantitative Comparison and Policy Analysis of Chile and Brazil., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Greene, Christina, Creating Truth Commissions: Transnational Advocacy Networks and Transitional Justice., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Grey, Tracy, Silicon Switch: The Decline of the United States vis a vis Japan in DRAMs., 1990 (Box 16)
  - Griffoli, Tommaso Mancini, The Parable of the CAP- Behind the Scenes of Brussels, Through Rome and to the Italian Countryside; Towards a More Satisfactory Theory of Social Interaction., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Haller, Joseph R., The Yugoslav Crisis: An Historical Perspective., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Hampe, Carl, The Foreign Policy of Mexico and Venezuela toward Central America and the Caribbean Basin., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Handeyside, Hugh, U.S. Democracy Assistance Organizations in Post-Cold War Russia., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Harrigan, Sarah, When States Buck the International Norm: A comparative Analysis of American and Japanese Policy Approaches to Burma, Iran and North Korea., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Harrison, Michéle, The Palestinian Cause in the Politics of Gamal Abdel Nasser, 1967-70., 1986 (Box 12)
  - Havriliuc, Tudor, The Miners' Republic: A Political Analysis of the History of the Mining Sector in Romania., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Heredia, Alexandra Salcedo, A Profile of Street Children in Caracas, Venezuela., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Hileman, Ali, Politics of Performances and Performances of Politics: South African Theater for Development and its Effect on the Dismantling of Apartheid., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Hilgeman, Erica, Scapegoat or Legitimate Compliant? The American and Japanese Business-Health Care Relationship., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Hill, Jennifer, Communications, Sovereignty, and Cultural Identity: An examination of media response to nationhood in Catalonia., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Hollenback, Elizabeth A., The Transport Dimension of Climate Change: Passenger Vehicles in the German and European Union Policy Processes., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Hooton, Michael, Canadian Nuclear Aid to India and the 1974 Atomic Blast--The Effect on Global Nuclear Proliferation Politics., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Hornung, Leslie, Jean Monnet and the Development of the Common Market., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Hsieh, Lilli, Regional Conflict: The Political Impasse Between the ROC and the PRC With Respect to the Reunification of China., 1995 (Box 29)
  - Hsin, Amy, Narrating Identity on Taiwan: Public Discourse on the 1947 February 28 Incident., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Htun, Mala Nani, The Struggle for Political Hegemony and a One-Party State in Zimbabwe., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Hwang, Irene, Lobbying for Independence: The Korean Nationalist Movement in Extile in the United States, 1941-1945., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Isaacs, James, Sir Isaac Newton and Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz: "How?" vs. "Why?"., 1982 (Box 7)
  - Jeans, Peter, The Democratization of the German Political Culture., 1993 (Box 23)
  - Jelescu, Diana, The Domino Theory of European Integration: The Case of Romania., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Jeng, Irene, Reforming the Socialist System: A Comparison of the Chinese and Soviet Experience., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Jhaveri, Suha, Simone de Beauvoir: A Cultural/Political Analysis of The Second Sex and Its Effect On French, Italian and American Feminism., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Allison Marie, Development and the Military in Latin America: The Economic Policy, Politics and Political Decisions of the Brazilian and Peruvian Military Regimes: Between 1960 and 1975., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Johnson, Arbora, Takako Doi-Female Politician in Japan., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Johnson, Gregg, French Security Policy under Jacques Chirac: The Gaullist Tradition in the Post-Cold War Era., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Johnson, Marlowe, Who Owns Namibia? South Africa's Continuing Colonial Domination., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Johnson, Robert Alan, The French Left and Strategic Nuclear Forces., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Jones, Keltie, The Reconciliation of the White Community in Zimbabwe, 1980-1988. (Box 13)
  - Kang, Barry, Food Security and International Relations Theory: A Comparative Study of North and South Korea., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Kang, David, Domestic Factors Influencing the Prospects for Unification on the Korean Peninsula., 1987 (Box 12)
  - Kaufman, Leslie, Changing the Balance of Power: The War Powers Act 15 Years Later, 1988; 1 folder(s)
  - Kaval, David A., United States' Policy on European Integration: From the Treaty of Rome to Easter European Enlargement., 1998 (Box 35)
  - Kelso, Matt, Emerging Stock Markets in Argentina and Chile: Explanations for Equities Market Development., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Kelso, Matthew A., Continuity and Change: An Assessment of Post-War German Security Policy., 1995 (Box 28)
  - Kettner, Eric, Developments Leading up to the Sino-Vietnamese War of 1979: The Chinese use of Coercive Diplomacy., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Keyes, Melissa H., US-Japan Cooperation on Global Sustainable Development., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Kim, Caroline Y., Semicolor Production: industrial differences in America, Japan, and Korea., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Kim, Cindy Kyunglim, The Japanese Bureaucracy and Public Policy., 1996 (Box 30)
  - King, Blair A., John F. Kennedy and the Palestinian Refugees: The Changing Role of the United States in Southwest Asia, 1961-63"., 1989 (Box 15)
  - King, Debra, Central and Eastern Europe and the Future of the European Union: The Politics and Economics of Accession., 1997 (Box 33)
  - Kirkpatrick, Lisa Anne, The Algerian Oil Industry: A Model for Development., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Knickrehm, Kate E., Dissidence in Eastern Europe: The case of East Germany., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Kraft, Diana, The Effect of an Integration Process on Comparatively Lesser- Developed Economies: Spain and Mexico as Case Studies., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Kramer, Mark Nathan, The Soviet Union and Eastern Europe: Reform, Revolution, and Intervention., 1982 (Box 8)
  - Krass, Caroline Diane, The INF Treaty and the Future of NATO: West European Reactions to a Changing Security Environment., 1989 (Box 15)
  - Kuan, Jennifer, Political Transition in the Philippines and the Role of the Military., 1987 (Box 13)
  - Kuo, Renée Claire, Drinking Buddies: a study of foreign direct investment in China's beer industry., 1997 (Box 34)
  - La Hood, Lila Marie, A History of Regional Cooperation in the Maghreb., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Lai, Christina, Reunification versus Independence: Nationalism and Domestic Political Development in the Republic of China., 1993 (Box 24)
  - Lampton, Gerald R., Chile and the Italian Left: The Fall of Allende and the Strategy of the Italian Communist Party., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Lange, Lance W., Regionalism in Europe: An Evaluation of the Relationship between the German Federal States and the European Union., 1996 (Box 30)
  - Lari, Sanam, The Status of Women in Post-Revolutionary Iran: An Unlikely Alliance between Feminism and Islam., 1997 (Box 34)
  - Lau, Christina, Ecotourism and Local Economic Development: A Look at Monteverde and Santa Elena, Costa Rica., 1998 (Box 36)
  - Lean, Eugenia, The Relationship between Culture and Politics in Communist Regimes: A Comparative Analysis of China and the Soviet Union., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Lee, Eun Hwa, Altering the Course of the Han River Water From Different Angels and with "Modern" Tools: Disparate Voices from the Contemporary South Korean Women's Movement about Its History, Intellectual Antecedents, and Activities., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Letteau, Gabrielle Tracey, The Perils of Proliferation: An Examination into the Implications of Proliferation on the Korean Peninsula., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Liao, Leslie, Emerging from the Political Chrysalis: The Chinese Diaspora, A Study of Increased Politicization via Globalization., 1999 (Box 38)
  - Liberman, Enrique, Making the Argument for Central Bank Independence: The Case of Argentina from 1983-1995., 1996 (Box 31)
  - Lim, Caroline A., Building Community Self-Reliance: An Examination of Factors Leading to Success in Grassroots Development., 1989 (Box 16)
  - Lindermayr, Nicole Elisabeth, Two-Tiered Approach or Double Agenda? How Germany Changed its Immigration Laws 1989-1995. (Box 28)
  - Lindheim, Susan, Implications of Argentine-Brazilian Nuclear Cooperation for Non-Proliferation., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Liu, Caitlin M., The Role of Land Reform in the Postwar Economic Development of Taiwan., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Lloyd, Charles, The Development of Hungary's Relations with the European Community During The Post-Communist Reforms., 1990 (Box 17)
  - Lobel, Richard S., "The Middle Ground" How John F. Kennedy's Military Policies in Vietnam Were Shaped by Domestic Factors., 1992 (Box 21)
  - Londgren, Michael, Britain and Economic and Monetary Union in the European Community., 1991 (Box 19)
  - Loofbourrow, Patrick, Attitudes Toward and Participation in Mandatory Military Conscription in Ecuador: A General Ethnography., 1988 (Box 13)
  - Loubé, Suzanne A., The History of the Political Decision-Making Process in Micronesia: A Key to Micronesia's Political Indecisiveness., 1980 (Box 5)
  - Lung, Michael P. Lum, The Continental Commitment vs. Maritime Strategy: Competing Styles of War 1945-2000., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Luxon, Nancy, The Cross and the Crown: The Polish Catholic Church and Politics since 1989., 1995 (Box 28)
  - MacWilliams, John J., International Terrorism: Communication through Violence., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Mandel, Billie Michele, Conflict Resolution in Nicaragua: The Autonomy of the Ethnic Minorities of the Atlantic Coast., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Martin, Paul A., Puerto Rico's Operation Bootstrap and Mexico's Maquiladoras: Possible Long-Term Consequences of Mexico's Border Industrialization Program., 1988 (Box 13)
  - Martinez, Elisa Marie, Mexican Immigration to the United States in A Historical Context., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Maurer, Noël H., Profits and Power in the Porfiriato: The Rate of Return in Mexican Business Enterprise 1900-10., 1992 (Box 23)
  - McCoy, Elizabeth, China's Special Economic Zones., 1989 (Box 16)
  - McCoy, Meri, The Third United Nations Conference on the Law of the Sea: A Case Study on the Formulation of National Interest., 1985 (Box 10)
  - McFaul, Michael, Crises in Eastern Europe: Soviet Decision-Making and American Foreign Policy., 1986 (Box 12)
  - McGovern, John, Relations between the United States and Nicaragua: The Carter Administration Precedent., 1987 (Box 13)
  - McMillen, R. Scott, Breaking Through the Wall: An Analysis of Human Rights in the Two Germanies., 1985 (Box 10)
  - Meinl, Thomas, The U.S. and European International Political Economy and Security: Focus Studies., 1994 (Box 25)
  - Merkley, Jeffrey A., The Impact of Policies and Programs of the United States upon Political Conditions in Iran during the Reign of Mohammed Riza Shah Pahlavi., 1979 (Box 3)
  - Mertz, Steven W., Charles DeGaulle Versus Great Britain: The Long Struggle for British Entry into the European Economic Community., 1979 (Box 4)
  - Meyers, Irina, Ukraine's Foreign Policy vis-à-vis Russia: From Confrontation to Compromise., 1994 (Box 26)
  - Miccolis, Eduardo, Communication Satellites: Has This Technology widened the Gap Between Less Developed Countries (LCDs) and Highly Developed Countries (HCDs)., 1988 (Box 13)